Adeniyi **Adetunji**

A DevOps Engineer with background developing, designing, testing and implementing infrastructure and applications. Talented performer with over 10 years of experience developing programmes (web, mobile and desktop) and pipelines, using source control tools to identify and fix bugs in code. Consistent team player with exemplary multitasking skills.

29, Agboyi Road, Alapere, Ketu, Lagos, Nigeria (+234) 07036568933 adenadet@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

St. Nicholas Hospital, Lagos Island, Lagos *IT Supervisor – Softwares*

OCT 2020 - PRESENT

Interfacing with vendor for deployment of a new Electronic Medical Records / Health Information Management System

Developed and Deployed an Office Management System with various sub systems including Document Manager, Learning Management System, Policy Management, Chats, Ticket Management and various sub systems for Office use.

Guided organizational technology strategy and roadmaps.

Led technology selection and rollout, focusing on organizational planning and supplier service-level agreements.

Demonstrated familiarity with latest hardware, software and networking technology.

Oversaw IT department operations and training.

Understood key product management roadmap objectives and requirements to develop product technology strategy.

Assisted in the development of long-term strategies to grow the department.

Wrote policy, procedure and manuals governing internal IT use.

Customized and repaired technology based on staff requests.

Squarem Knight Prince Consultancy, Ketu, Lagos *DevOps Engineer*

April 2020 - November 2020

Monitored automated build and continuous software integration process to drive build/release failure resolution.

Worked with cross-functional design teams to create software solutions that improved overall functionality and performance.

Implemented best practices to protect data and assets.

SKILLS

Versioning Tools: Git

CI: Jenkins

Ticket Tracking Tool: JIRA

Containerization: Docker,

Kubernetes

Operating Systems: Windows, UNIX

AWS: Amazon EC2, S3, RDS, ELB, EBS, Auto Scaling

Big Data: Hadoop, HDFS, MapReduce, Flume, Pig, Sqoop, Hive, oozie, MongoDB

ETL: Ab Initio

Monitoring Tool: Nagios

Databases: Oracle, MongoDB, MySQL, MariaDB

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP, Python

RDMS Development and SQL

Scrum Methodology

DevOps Systems

Software Deployment

Web Programming

Linux Environments

Data Warehousing and Analytics

Deployment Monitoring

Investigated new and emerging software applications to select and implement administrative information systems.

Wrote code and supported architecture in high-throughput systems.

Supervised software life cycle from preliminary needs analysis to enterprise-wide deployment and support.

Huawei Technologies Nigeria, Victoria Island, Lagos Data Analyst / Developer

January 2019 - April 2020

Worked with Globalcom's business intelligence software and various reports to glean insights into trends and prospects.

Identified, analyzed and interpreted trends or patterns in complex data sets from various Call Data Records (CDRs) including Subscription viability and generation of several reports for Globalcom's business and marketing needs.

Documented effective and replicable methods for extracting data and organizing data sources.

Researched and resolved issues regarding integrity of data flow into databases.

Identified and documented detailed business rules and use cases based on requirements analysis.

Analyzed transactions to build logical business intelligence model for real-time reporting needs.

Developed tables, views and materialized views using SQL.

Create and manage various pipelines for processing of various Call Data Records (CDRs) and tested data prediction algorithms based on historical data.

OrangeApple Technologies Limited, Lekki Phase I, Lagos *Lead Software Developer*

October 2015 - December 2018

Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.

Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development. Coordinated with project management on database development timelines.

Designed customized solutions for proposals to potential customers in the Public sector (Electronic Motor Vehicle Licensing) and the Education Sector.

AWARDS

Most Tickets Closed By An FOE

LM Ericsson Nigeria, 2016.

Medical Director's Award for Performance,

St. Nicholas Hospital, 2022

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

PHP Framework:
Laravel,
Javascript Framework:
JQuery, VueJS, AngularJS
Python Framework:
Flask, Django, Kivy

CERTIFICATIONS

PMI-ACP®, SkillUp - 2022

Certified MongoDB Administrator - 2022

Certified MongoDB Developer - 2022

Data Visualization using Python, Great Learning
Academy - 2021

Full Stack Development with Flask,

Pirple Academy - 2022

Introduction to DevOps, Great Learning Academy -2021

Introduction to Information
Security,
Creat learning Academy

Great learning Academy -2021

MySQL Basics, Great Learning Academy -2021

Software Testing

Fundamentals, Great Learning Academy - 2021

Introduced agile methodologies and development best practices to division to enhance product development. This ensured that project delivery and customer satisfaction went hand in hand.

Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.

Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve user experience.

Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.

Developed software for web and mobile operating systems. Also integrated with a POS machine using APIs.

Integrated softwares with the Nigeria Inter-Bank Settlement System Plc (NIBSS) for Financial transaction accruement and other payments.

Led version control efforts for organization, employing public and open source repositories.

Documented technical workflows and knowledge to educate newly hired employees. This included the creation of various manuals and policy documentation.

LM Ericsson Nigeria, Victoria Island, Lagos Front Office Engineer

July 2014 - September 2015

Collaborated with Field Service Engineers to ensure that the site availability roses from 93% to 97% between April 2015 and July 2015.

Handled several calls per day to address customer inquiries and concerns. As well as inform Field Service Engineers on site availability issues and keep the entire escalation matrix in the know of critical failures on the MTN network

Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.

Participated in team-building activities to enhance working relationships.

Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.

Won awards for Closing the most amount of Incident Tickets in 2015.

EDUCATION

National Open University of Nigeria, Lagos Island, Lagos, — *Master of Science, Information Technology*

June 2023

University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Kwara — Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical Engineering